Erskine Caldwell Papers
Erskine Caldwell Papers
1936-1942
Caldwell, Erskine, 1903-1987
8 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, dramatist, journalist, novelist, screenwriter, short story writer. Correspondence, financial records, writings, notes, telegrams, manuscripts, and memorabilia, spanning the seven years of the author's professional and personal relationship with photojournalist Margaret Bourke-White.
Writings
146312
Biographical History
Erskine Caldwell (1903-1987) was an American author known for writing about the American South. Caldwell grew up in the South (Virginia, Tennessee, Georgia, and North and South Carolina) and his novels -- the most famous of which are Tobacco Road and God's Little Acre -- deal with problems faced by Southerners in the mid-twentieth century including poverty and racism. His second wife was the noted photojournalist Margaret Bourke-White.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Erskine Caldwell Papers comprise 16 boxes of correspondence-subject files, writings, financial materials, and memorabilia documenting the 7 year span of the author's professional and intense personal relationship with photojournalist Margaret Bourke-White. Acquired as part of the Margaret Bourke-White Papers, there are few materials in the collection either before 1936 or after 1942, the year the couple divorced.
Correspondence-subject files are arranged alphabetically in 7 archival boxes and include business and professional files as well as personal and biographical materials. Correspondence which is of the greatest depth and duration includes that of Margaret Bourke-White, parents Ira and Caroline Caldwell, former wife Helen Caldwell Cushman, publishers Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Inc., agent Maxim Lieber, Life, artist Alfred Morang, PM, attorney Julius Weiss, and Caldwell and Bourke-White secretaries Margaret Salter and Margaret Smith, both of whom presided over the couple's often long-distance correspondences.
Writings comprise articles about the Russian front, typescript manuscripts and/or production records of books, short stories, production records, scripts, including untitled radio scripts from Moscow; miscellaneous drafts, typescript manuscripts, and notes on trips; press wireless releases Caldwell sent from Moscow while covering the German invasion of Russia for Life and PM; and printed short stories. They are arranged by type in 2 archival boxes and are almost solely works by Caldwell. Box 8 contains articles about the Russian front; typescript manuscripts and/or production records of books (God's Little Acre, Southways, Tobacco Road); production records of You Have Seen Their Faces (in collaboration with Bourke-White); scripts, including untitled radio scripts from Moscow; and typescript manuscripts of short stories. Box 9 contains miscellaneous drafts, typescript manuscripts, and notes on trips as well as press wireless releases Caldwell sent from Moscow while covering the German invasion of Russia for Life and PM, and printed short stories.
Financial materials (Boxes 9-15) include 3 years of cancelled checks, various household receipts (from grocery, utility and landscaping bills to car information and poll tax receipts), 4 years of royalty statements from the London, New York, and road company productions of Tobacco Road, and stocks and bonds information.
Memorabilia comprises addresses, clippings, contracts, publicity flyers, recipes, Caldwell's wallet and contents, a 1939 will, and miscellaneous printed material. Box 16 contains mostly personal photos of Caldwell and Bourke-White at their home, with their pets, or traveling and working together, some or which were taken by Bourke-White. There are some publicity photos and a few pre-1936 pictures of Caldwell's first wife and children.
Related Material
See also the Margaret Bourke-White Papers.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radicalism; Journalism; Dance and theatre; Literature -- American Fiction; Bourke-White, Margaret, 1904-1971.; Caldwell, Erskine, 1903-1987.; Caldwell, Helen.; Caldwell, Ira Sylvester, 1870-1944.; Lieber, Maxim.; Morang, Alfred, 1901-1958.; Life (New York, N.Y.); New Masses.; PM (New York, N.Y.); Authors, American.; Dramatists -- United States.; Journalists -- Family relationships.; Journalists -- United States.; Novelists, American.; Photographers -- United States.; Screenwriters -- United States.; Short stories, American -- 20th century.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Journalists.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Campaigns -- Russia (Federation); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Bank statements.; Bills of sale.; Check stubs.; Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Receipts (financial records); Authors.; Dramatists.; Journalists.; Novelists.; Screenwriters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence - subject files
  - A, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Accent, See Harris, Marguerite Tjader.
  - Allen, Jay, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Alliance Book Corporation, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Alvarez del Vayo, Julio, 1940 (Box 1)
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, See Hemingway, Ernest.
  - American Council Against Nazi Propaganda, Inc., 1939 (Box 1)
  - American Folkways, See Corle, Edwin; Kennedy, Stetson; Long, Haniel; Rayburn, Otto Ernest; Thane, Eric; Thomas, Jeannette; Vestal, Stanley.
  - American Jewish Congress. Women's Division, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Anti-Fascist Foundation, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Appel, Benjamin, 1940; undated (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Brooks, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Authors' Guild of the Authors' League of America, See Authors' League of America, Inc.
  - Authors' League of America, Inc., 1937-1940 (Box 1)
  - B, 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Bailey, James Osler, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Basso, Hamilton, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Beals, Carleton, undated (Box 1)
  - Behn, Harry, 1939-1940 (Box 1)
  - Behrens, Jacob, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Earl L. and Emma, 1938-1940; undated (Box 1)
  - Bernadotte, Folke, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Best, Marshall A., See Viking Press, Inc.
  - Billings, John Shaw, See Life.
  - Birk, Louis P., See Modern Age Books, Inc.
  - Bishop, John Peale, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Blassingame, Lurton, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Bliven, Bruce, See New Republic.
  - Block, Harry, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Bombal, Maria Luisa, undated (Box 1)
  - Bourke-White, Margaret, 1936-1939; 6 folders (Box 1)
  - Bourke-White, Margaret, 1940-1942; 1959,; undated; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Braniff, Edward A., 1938 (Box 2)
  - Brentano's Booksellers, 1939-1940 (Box 2)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Henry Tatnall, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Brush, Katharine, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Bulkley, Louise, 1942; undated (Box 2)
  - Burger, Hans, undated (Box 2)
  - Burnett, Whit, 1939-1940 (Box 2)
  - Burrelle's, 1938-1940 (Box 2)
  - Busch, Noel F., See Life.
  - Byrd, Sam, 1939 (Box 2)
  - C, 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Caldwell, Helen, See Cushman, Helen.
  - Caldwell, Ira Sylvester and Caroline Preston (Bell), 1937; 1939-1940,; undated (Box 2)
  - Caldwell children, 1937-1940 (Box 2)
  - Calmer, Alan, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Walter Stanley, See Vestal, Stanley.
  - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Carlson, Avis, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Catlin, Stanton L., 1938 (Box 2)
  - Cerf, Bennett, 1938-1939 (Box 2)
  - Cheever, Lawrence Oakley, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Chemical Bank & Trust Company, 1939-1940; See also Financial: Chemical Bank and Trust Co. (Box 2)
  - Coindreau, Maurice Edgar, 1934; 1939,; undated (Box 2)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc. (CBS), 1941 (Box 2)
  - Conference on Pan American Democracy, 1938-1939 (Box 2)
  - Conroy, Jack, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Corle, Edwin, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Cosulich, Bernice, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Cousins, Norman, See Saturday Review of Literature.
  - Coxe, Daniel, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Cunningham, William, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Cushman, Helen, 1938-1940; undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Czechoslovak Consulate General, 1938 (Box 3)
  - D, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Daily Sketch (London), 1941 (Box 3)
  - Daniels, Frank, undated (Box 3)
  - Davis, Lambert, See Bobbs-Merrill Company.
  - Dean, Alexander, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Direction, See Harris, Marguerite Tjader.
  - Dodd, William Edward, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Dolphin, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Dombroski, James, See Highlander Folk School.
  - Dorrance, Ward Allison, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Doughty, LeGarde S., 1940 (Box 3)
  - Dowling, Eddie, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Dramatists' Guild of the Authors' League of America, 1937-1939 (Box 3)
  - Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Inc., 1939-1941; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Durant, Genevieve, See Durant, Kenneth and Genevieve.
  - Durant, Kenneth and Genevieve ("Jed"), 1938-1941 (Box 3)
  - E, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Efron, David, See Conference on Pan American Democracy.
  - Elliott, Charles N., 1939-1940 (Box 3)
  - Everitt, C. Raymond, See Little, Brown, & Company.
  - F, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Ferguson, Otis, See New Republic.
  - Field, Ben, 1938-1940 (Box 3)
  - Fischer, Louis and Markoosha, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Foley, Martha, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Foreign Commission of Soviet Writers of the USSR, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Friede, Donald, 1939 (Box 3)
  - G, 1 folder (Box 3)
  - Gallimard, Claude, undated (Box 3)
  - Gannett, Lewis, See New York Herald Tribune.
  - Gates, Arnold F., 1939 (Box 3)
  - Geer, William and Herta, 1939; undated (Box 3)
  - Gillmor, Frances, 1940; undated (Box 3)
  - Goldstone, Nat C., 1940; undated (Box 3)
  - Golenpaul, Dan, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Gorelik, Mordecai, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Graebner, Walter, See Life.
  - Gussman, Lawrence, See Redbook Magazine.
  - H, 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Hampton, Vernon B., See Edwin Markham Memorial Association.
  - Hanc, Josef, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Harris, Marguerite Tjader, 1940; undated (Box 4)
  - Hartman, Ralph D., 1940 (Box 4)
  - Haycroft, Howard, See H. W. Wilson Company.
  - Hearst Strike Committee, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Hellman, Lillian, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Henry, Ralph Chester, See Thane, Eric.
  - Herrick, Frances, 1939-1940? (Box 4)
  - Hervey, Harry, 1940; undated (Box 4)
  - Hicks, Wilson, See Life.
  - Highlander Folk School, 1937; 1939-1940,; undated (Box 4)
  - Horton, Myles, See Highlander Folk School.
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1940 (Box 4)
  - I (Box 4)
  - Ingersoll, Ralph, See PM.
  - International Literature, See Rokotov, T.
  - J, 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Johns, Richard, 1938-1939; undated (Box 4)
  - Jones, Alfred W., 1939 (Box 4)
  - K, 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Karr, David, 1942 (Box 4)
  - Kelm, Karlton, undated (Box 4)
  - Kennedy, Stetson, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Kirk, Barbara, 1939; undated (Box 4)
  - Kline, Herbert, undated (Box 4)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1940 (Box 4)
  - Kocourek, Rotislav, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Kopperl, Bert, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Korner, Ruth, 1938-1939; undated (Box 4)
  - Kronenberger, Louis, See PM.
  - Kunitz, Stanley, See H. W. Wilson Company.
  - L, 1 folder (Box 4)
  - Lane, Mrs. Julian Carswell, 1939 (Box 4)
  - League of American Writers, 1938-1941; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Lengel, William Charles, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, H. H., 1940 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, John, See PM, 1941.
  - Lieber, Maxim, 1937-1939; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Lieber, Maxim, 1940-1941; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Lieberson, Margaret, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Life, 1941; undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Little, Brown, & Company, 1939-1940 (Box 5)
  - Long, Haniel, 1939-1941; undated (Box 5)
  - Luce, Henry and Clare (Box 5)
    See also Life.
  - Lynn, Rhoda, 1940-1941; undated (Box 5)
  - Lyon, John Henry Hobart, 1939 (Box 5)
  - Lyons, Leonard, 1939; undated (Box 5)
  - M, 1 folder (Box 5)
  - McBride, Mary Margaret, undated (Box 5)
  - Macdonald, Dwight, 1939 (Box 5)
  - Mack, Walter S., 1940 (Box 5)
  - Macleod, Norman, 1939-1940; undated (Box 5)
  - Macy, George, See Dolphin.
  - Magil, Abraham Bernard, See New Masses.
  - Maltz, Albert, 1940 (Box 5)
  - March of Time Limited, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Edwin Markham Memorial Association, 1940 (Box 5)
  - A. N. Marquis Company, 1939-1940 (Box 5)
  - Maxwell, William, See The New Yorker.
  - Meloney, Marie Mattingly, See New York Herald Tribune.
  - Mermelstein, Martin, 1938-1941 (Box 5)
  - Miller, Ellen B., 1940 (Box 5)
  - Miller, Nellie Burget, See Miller, Ellen B.
  - Mitchell, Joseph, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Modern Age Books, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Moe, Henry Allen, 1937; 1940 (Box 5)
  - Molotov, Vyacheslav Mikhaylovich, 1941 (Box 5)
  - Montague Paramount News, 1941 (Box 5)
  - Morang, Alfred, 1936; 1939-1941 (Box 5)
  - Morang, Alfred, drawings: pen, watercolor (Box 5)
  - Motion Picture Democratic Committee, 1939 (Box 5)
  - Mullins, Helene, 1939 (Box 5)
  - Mumford, Lewis, See American Council Against Nazi Propaganda, Inc.
  - N, 1 folder (Box 5)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) (Box 5)
  - National Committee For People's Rights, 1938-1939 (Box 5)
  - National Foundation for Infantile Paralysis, Inc., 1938 (Box 5)
  - Nelson, Truman, 1940 (Box 5)
  - New Masses, 1939-1940 (Box 5)
  - New Republic, 1938-1940; undated (Box 6)
  - New School for Social Research, 1937-1938; undated (Box 6)
  - New York Committee of Fifty-Six, 1939 (Box 6)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1939-1941 (Box 6)
  - New York Post, See Lyons, Leonard.
  - The New Yorker, 1938-1940; undated (Box 6)
  - Nix, Ann, 1940; caricature of Caldwell (Box 6)
  - North, Joseph, See New Masses.
  - O, 1 folder (Box 6)
  - O'Brien, Edward Joseph, 1940-1941 (Box 6)
  - O'Donnell, Edwin P., 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - Orton, Vrest, 1939-1940; undated (Box 6)
  - Oumansky, K., 1941 (Box 6)
  - P, 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Page, Myra, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Pardoe, T. Earl, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Pearce, Charles A. (Box 6)
    See also Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Inc.
  - P.E.N., 1939 (Box 6)
  - Perry, Claire W., See Perry, Clay.
  - Perry, Clay, 1940 (Box 6)
  - PM, 1939-1941; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Pringle, Ernest Henry, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Q (Box 6)
  - Quinn, Kerker, See Harris, Marguerite Tjader.
  - R, 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Raffalovich, George, 1939 (Box 6)
  - Rayburn, Otto Ernest, 1934; 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - Redbook Magazine, undated (Box 6)
  - Reissig, Herman F., 1939 (Box 6)
  - Robertson, Ben, 1939 (Box 6)
  - Rokotov, T., 1937-1940 (Box 6)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1939 (Box 6)
  - Rose, Stanley, 1939-1940; undated (Box 6)
  - Rosenbach, A. S. W., 1940 (Box 6)
  - Russian War Relief, 1941 (Box 6)
  - S, 1 folder (Box 6)
  - Salter, Margaret and John, 1938-1940; undated (Box 6)
  - Saturday Review of Literature, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Schacher, Gerhard, 1939 (Box 6)
  - Seaver, Edwin, 1938 (Box 6)
  - Selby, John, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - Sellers, Jack, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Showshop, Inc., 1937 (Box 7)
  - Simon and Schuster Publishers, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Smith, Jessica, See Soviet Russia Today.
  - Smith, Margaret, 1937-1940 (Box 7)
  - Southern Women's National Democratic Organization in New York, Inc., 1940-1941 (Box 7)
  - Soviet Russia Today, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Spanish Refugee Relief Campaign, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Stagg, Jerry, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Steinhardt, Laurence, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Steloff, Frances, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Stern, Alfred Kaufman, 1939-1941 (Box 7)
  - Stewart, Donald F., See PM.
  - Stoddard, Alfred, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Sunday Chronicle, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Sure, Ethel, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Szilasi, Bela, 1938 (Box 7)
  - T, 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Taggard, Genevieve, See Durant, Kenneth and Genevieve.
  - Thane, Eric, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Thomas, Jeannette, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Thompson, Clara, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Thompson, Edward K., See Life.
  - Thorndike, Joseph, See Life.
  - Tilgham, Zoe A., 1940 (Box 7)
  - Town & Country, 1938 (Box 7)
  - Trout, Bob, 1939 (Box 7)
  - U, 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Underwood, Edna Worthley, 1940 (Box 7)
  - United States Department of State, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Urey, Harold Clayton, 1939 (Box 7)
  - V, 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Van Doren, Irita, See New York Herald Tribune.
  - Van Vechten, Carl, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Vassar College Political Association, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Vestal, Stanley, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
  - Viking Press, Inc., 1938-1940 (Box 7)
  - Von Carlshousen, H. Buderus, 1940 (Box 7)
  - W, 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Weiss, Julius, 1937-1941; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - West, Nathanael ("Pep W."), 1939 (Box 7)
  - White, Paul, See Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc.
  - White, Ruth, 1938-1940 (Box 7)
  - H. W. Wilson Company, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Winter, Ella, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Wise, Louise W. (Mrs. Stephen S.), See American Jewish Congress. Women's Division.
  - Woollacott, Arthur P., 1940 (Box 7)
  - World Broadcasting System, Inc., 1940 (Box 7)
  - Y, 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Z (Box 7)
  - Zinn, Mildred, 1940; undated (Box 7)
  - Unidentified, 1938-1940; undated (Box 7)
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "Behind Russian Lines", July 28, 1941; draft of article which appeared in Life (Box 8)
    - "Russia in Wartime", Sept. 8, 1941; draft of article which appeared in Life (Box 8)
  - Books
    - God's Little Acre, motion picture option; See Correspondence-subject files: Goldstone, Nat C.
    - Russia at War, ms. (Box 8)
    - Southways, ms. (Box 8)
    - Southways, production records - galleys (Box 8)
    - Tobacco Road, production records - illustrations (Box 8)
    - You Have Seen Their Faces, production records - dust jacket (Box 8)
    - You Have Seen Their Faces, production records - "Order of Caldwell Prints In Book" (Box 8)
  - Scripts
    - "Journeyman", production records - financial (Box 8)
    - Untitled radio scripts (Soviet Union), June 30, 1941; Aug. 1941; ms.; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Untitled radio scripts (Soviet Union), Sept. 1941; ms. (Box 8)
  - Stories
    - "Big Buck", ms. (Box 8)
    - "The Courting of Susie Brown", ms. (Box 8)
    - "The Day the Presidential Candidate Came to Ciudad Tamaulipas", ms. (Box 8)
    - "Dine and Dance", ms. (Box 8)
    - "An Evening in Nuevo Leon", ms. (Box 8)
    - "The Fly in the Coffin", ms. (Box 8)
    - "The Long Road", ms. (Box 8)
    - "Roadside", ms. (Box 8)
    - "Runaway", ms. (Box 8)
    - "Shorty's Place", ms. (Box 8)
    - "Squire Dinwiddy", ms. (Box 8)
    - "Sylvia", ms. (Box 8)
    - "The Thunderstorm", ms. (Box 8)
    - "The Time They Jailed My Old Man", ms. (Box 8)
    - "Uncle Jeff", ms. (Box 8)
    - "The Windfall", ms. (Box 8)
  - Miscellany
    - "My Old Man", ms. (Box 9)
    - Notes on trips, 1936; 1937,; 1939,; 1940; 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Press wireless releases, Soviet Union to Life, typed sheets (Box 9)
      See also Unidentified drafts.
    - Press wireless releases, Soviet Union to PM, typed sheets (Box 9)
    - "Solomon Lozorsky", typed sheets (Box 9)
    - "Stalin", typed sheets (Box 9)
    - "Transit China", typed sheets (Box 9)
    - "Transit China", notes (Box 9)
    - Unidentified drafts, includes piece on Laurence A. Steinhardt which mention Lillie Langtry, and a number of copies of press wireless releases sent from the Soviet Union (recipient is not identified) (Box 9)
      See also Press wireless releases, Soviet Union to Life and Press wireless releases, Soviet Union to PM.
  - Printed material
    - "Hamrick's Polar Bear" - Red Book, July 1937 (Box 9)
    - "Here and Today" - Harper's Bazaar, Feb. 1937 (Box 9)
    - "Home Front - Texas Style" - New York Herald Tribune, May 10, 1942 (Box 9)
    - "In Defense Of Myself", publication unidentified (Box 9)
    - "A Knife to Cut the Cornbread With" - Direction, Jan. 1938 (Box 9)
    - "Man and Woman" - The New Yorker, July 10, 1937 (Box 9)
    - "The Night My Old Man Came Home" - The New Yorker, Dec. 11, 1937 (Box 9)
    - "Nine Dollars Worth of Mumble" - Harper's Bazaar, Mar. 1937 (Box 9)
    - "A Small Day" - The New Yorker, Aug. 22, 1936 (Box 9)
    - "Uncle Mose's Love Nest" - Sunday Worker, Jan. 23, 1938 (Box 9)
    - "Warm River" - Redbook, Apr. 1938 (Box 9)
- Financial
  - Chemical Bank & Trust Co., 1937-1938; cancelled checks, deposits, statements; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Chemical Bank & Trust Co., 1939-1941; cancelled checks, deposits statements; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Chemical Bank & Trust Co., 1937-1940; custodial account #1; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Chemical Bank & Trust Co., 1937-1940; custodial account #2; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Chemical Bank & Trust Co., 1938-1939; notes (Box 11)
  - First National Granite Bank, 1937; deposits (Box 11)
  - Home Bank & Trust Co., 1939-1941; cancelled checks, deposits, statements; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Home Bank & Trust Co., 1940-1941; trust fund; See also Chemical Bank & Trust Co. custodian accounts #1, #2. (Box 11)
  - Household receipts, 1936-1938; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Household receipts, 1939-1942; 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Insurance & annuities, 1937-1941; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous financial, 1939-1940 (Box 12)
  - Royalty statements: books, 1937-1940 (Box 13)
  - Royalty statements: Tobacco Road: London, undated (Box 13)
  - Royalty statements: Tobacco Road: New York Company, 1937-1940; 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Royalty statements: Tobacco Road: Road Company, 1937-1938; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Royalty statements: Tobacco Road: Road Company, 1939-1940; 6 folders (Box 14)
  - Royalty statements: Tobacco Road: Road Company-Eastern U.S., 1939-1940 (Box 14)
  - Royalty statements: Trouble In July, 1940 (Box 14)
  - Savings banks, 1940; miscellaneous items (Box 14)
  - Stocks: invoices, memos, receipts, 1937-1938 (Box 14)
  - Stocks: invoices, memos, receipts, 1939 (Box 15)
  - Travel (customs), 1941 (Box 15)
  - Travel vouchers, 1937-1942; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - U.S. Government Bonds, 1939-1940 (Box 15)
- Memorabilia
  - Clippings (Box 15)
  - Contract for Say! This Is The U.S.A., 1952 (Box 15)
  - Contract for You Have Seen Their Faces, 1937 (Box 15)
  - Credit cards and memberships (Box 15)
  - Names and addresses, 1940 (Box 15)
  - Photographs, personal and publicity (Oversize 1)
  - Publicity flyers (Box 15)
  - Recipes (Box 15)
  - Will & testament, 1939 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous printed materials (Box 15)
  - Miscellany (Box 15)